  <legalnotice id="legalnotice">
	<para>
	  Dopušteno je kopiranje, distribucija i/ili izmjena ovog dokumenta pod
uvjetima GNU licence slobodne dokumentacije (GFDL), inačice 1.1 ili novije,
koju je izdala Fundacija slobodnog softvera sa "bez nepromijenjive sekcije",
"bez teksta na naslovnici" i "bez teksta na koricama".  Kopiju GFDL licence
možete pronaći <ulink type="help" url="ghelp:fdl">ovdje</ulink> ili u
datoteci COPYING-DOCS, distribuiranu uz ovaj priručnik.
         </para>
         <para> Ovaj priručnik je treći dio kolekcije GNOME priručnika distribuiranih pod
GFDL licencom.  Ako želite distribuirati ovaj priručnik odvojeno od ove
kolekcije, to možete učiniti dodavanje kopije ove licence uz priručnik, kao
što je objašnjeno u članku 6 ove licence.
	</para>

	<para>
	  Mnogi nazivi, koje tvrtke koriste za diferencijaciju svojih proizvoda i
usluga, proglašeni su zaštitnim znakom. Kada se takvi nazivi spominju u bilo
kojoj GNOME dokumentaciji, a članovima projekta GNOME dokumentacije se
skrene pozornost na zaštitne znakove, ona se pišu velikim početnim slovom.
	</para>

	<para>
	  DOKUMENT I IZMIJENJENE INAČICE DOKUMENTA SU DOSTUPNE POD UVJETIMA LICENCE
GNU SLOBODNE DOKUMENTACIJE  S DALJNJIM SHVAĆANJEM DA: <orderedlist>
		<listitem>
		  <para>DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND,
EITHER EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, WARRANTIES THAT
THE DOCUMENT OR MODIFIED VERSION OF THE DOCUMENT IS FREE OF DEFECTS
MERCHANTABLE, FIT FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE OR NON-INFRINGING. THE ENTIRE
RISK AS TO THE QUALITY, ACCURACY, AND PERFORMANCE OF THE DOCUMENT OR
MODIFIED VERSION OF THE DOCUMENT IS WITH YOU. SHOULD ANY DOCUMENT OR
MODIFIED VERSION PROVE DEFECTIVE IN ANY RESPECT, YOU (NOT THE INITIAL
WRITER, AUTHOR OR ANY CONTRIBUTOR) ASSUME THE COST OF ANY NECESSARY
SERVICING, REPAIR OR CORRECTION. THIS DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTY CONSTITUTES AN
ESSENTIAL PART OF THIS LICENSE. NO USE OF ANY DOCUMENT OR MODIFIED VERSION
OF THE DOCUMENT IS AUTHORIZED HEREUNDER EXCEPT UNDER THIS DISCLAIMER; AND
		  </para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		  <para>UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES AND UNDER NO LEGAL THEORY, WHETHER IN TORT (INCLUDING
NEGLIGENCE), CONTRACT, OR OTHERWISE, SHALL THE AUTHOR, INITIAL WRITER, ANY
CONTRIBUTOR, OR ANY DISTRIBUTOR OF THE DOCUMENT OR MODIFIED VERSION OF THE
DOCUMENT, OR ANY SUPPLIER OF ANY OF SUCH PARTIES, BE LIABLE TO ANY PERSON
FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OF
ANY CHARACTER INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, DAMAGES FOR LOSS OF GOODWILL,
WORK STOPPAGE, COMPUTER FAILURE OR MALFUNCTION, OR ANY AND ALL OTHER DAMAGES
OR LOSSES ARISING OUT OF OR RELATING TO USE OF THE DOCUMENT AND MODIFIED
VERSIONS OF THE DOCUMENT, EVEN IF SUCH PARTY SHALL HAVE BEEN INFORMED OF THE
POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES.
		  </para>
		</listitem>
	  </orderedlist>
	</para>
  </legalnotice>

