  <legalnotice id="legalnotice">
	<para>
	  この文書は、Free Software Foundation 発行の GNU Free Doucumentation License (GFDL)
のバージョン1.1
もしくは、それ以降のバージョンが定める条件のもとで複製、頒布、および/あるいは、改変することが許諾されています。変更不可部分、表カバーテキスト、裏カバーテキストは存在しません。GFDLのコピーは、以下の
<ulink type="help" url="ghelp:fdl">リンク</ulink> もしくは、このマニュアルと共に配布されている
COPYING-DOCS のファイル中にあります。
         </para>
         <para> このマニュアルは GFDL のもとで頒布される GNOME
マニュアルの一部です。このマニュアルの一部分のみ頒布したい場合は、ライセンスの6章で述べているように、マニュアルのライセンスのコピーを添付することで頒布可能になります。
	</para>

	<para>
	  企業は、自社の製品やサービスを区別するために使用する多くの名称が登録商標であると主張しています。これらの名称が GNOME
のドキュメント中に表記されており、GNOME
ドキュメンテーション・プロジェクトのメンバがこれらの登録商標に注意を払っている箇所では、すべて大文字にするか、最初の文字を大文字にしています。
	</para>

	<para>
	  DOCUMENT AND MODIFIED VERSIONS OF THE DOCUMENT ARE PROVIDED UNDER THE TERMS
OF THE GNU FREE DOCUMENTATION LICENSE WITH THE FURTHER UNDERSTANDING THAT:
<orderedlist>
		<listitem>
		  <para>DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND,
EITHER EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, WARRANTIES THAT
THE DOCUMENT OR MODIFIED VERSION OF THE DOCUMENT IS FREE OF DEFECTS
MERCHANTABLE, FIT FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE OR NON-INFRINGING. THE ENTIRE
RISK AS TO THE QUALITY, ACCURACY, AND PERFORMANCE OF THE DOCUMENT OR
MODIFIED VERSION OF THE DOCUMENT IS WITH YOU. SHOULD ANY DOCUMENT OR
MODIFIED VERSION PROVE DEFECTIVE IN ANY RESPECT, YOU (NOT THE INITIAL
WRITER, AUTHOR OR ANY CONTRIBUTOR) ASSUME THE COST OF ANY NECESSARY
SERVICING, REPAIR OR CORRECTION. THIS DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTY CONSTITUTES AN
ESSENTIAL PART OF THIS LICENSE. NO USE OF ANY DOCUMENT OR MODIFIED VERSION
OF THE DOCUMENT IS AUTHORIZED HEREUNDER EXCEPT UNDER THIS DISCLAIMER; AND
		  </para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		  <para>UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES AND UNDER NO LEGAL THEORY, WHETHER IN TORT (INCLUDING
NEGLIGENCE), CONTRACT, OR OTHERWISE, SHALL THE AUTHOR, INITIAL WRITER, ANY
CONTRIBUTOR, OR ANY DISTRIBUTOR OF THE DOCUMENT OR MODIFIED VERSION OF THE
DOCUMENT, OR ANY SUPPLIER OF ANY OF SUCH PARTIES, BE LIABLE TO ANY PERSON
FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OF
ANY CHARACTER INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, DAMAGES FOR LOSS OF GOODWILL,
WORK STOPPAGE, COMPUTER FAILURE OR MALFUNCTION, OR ANY AND ALL OTHER DAMAGES
OR LOSSES ARISING OUT OF OR RELATING TO USE OF THE DOCUMENT AND MODIFIED
VERSIONS OF THE DOCUMENT, EVEN IF SUCH PARTY SHALL HAVE BEEN INFORMED OF THE
POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES.
		  </para>
		</listitem>
	  </orderedlist>
	</para>
  </legalnotice>

